# SCOTT PATRICK DANCER

Vancouver, WA | (360) 953-7969

Email: scottpdancer@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/ScottDancer

Portfolio: <a href="https://spd-react-profile.herokuapp.com/home">https://spd-react-profile.herokuapp.com/home</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-dancer-9744091b2/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-dancer-9744091b2/</a>

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER | WEB DEVELOPER**

Full Stack Web Developer and Graphic Designer with a background in illustration, watercolor, and cartooning. Possess a strong foundation in communication, problem solving, and creativity that lends itself to building applications that are aesthetically pleasing and meet client expectations. Earned a Certificate in Web Development from the University of Washington.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/ECMAScript 6, SQL

**Applications:** Github, Heroku, mySQL, Postman

**Tools:** Bootstrap, Materialize, jQuery, Node.js, Express, Handlebars.js, ReactJS, MongoDB **Adobe:** Photoshop, Illustrator, Animate, InDesign, After Effects, Audition, Dreamweaver, XD

#### **PROJECTS**

## Achording to Jazz

https://github.com/ScottDancer/Music-Chord-Identifier | https://gnuartemis.github.io/Music-Chord-Identifier/index.html

**Achording to Jazz** uses complex algorithms to dissect chord information returned by APIs based on student note selection. It is designed to serve as a chord study tool for the elementary level music student. **Role:** Concept and name creation, resource development/api research, front-end to back-end connections. **Tools:** API-Reverse Chord Identifier, API-Chord Sound (for Piano Display and Progression), Materialize for design, Audiosynth.js and playKeyboard.js.

#### The Cold West

https://github.com/ScottDancer/project2\_| https://the-cold-west.herokuapp.com

**The Cold West** is a Washington State ski and snowboard travel guide. The user creates an account and searches winter resorts in their area.

**Role:** Concept and name creation, resource development, home and about us page design, original artwork, color design, front-end to back-end connections.

**Tools:** Materialize, Slick, Leaflet, MySql2, Express, Express-Handlebars, Express-session, bcrypt, dotenv, Sequelize, Adobe Illustrator and XD

## Indulge

https://github.com/mercspring/experience-indulgence | https://experience-indulgence.herokuapp.com

**Indulge** was conceived in the covid-19 era as a high end chef directory allowing upscale diners to find and hire their favorite chefs from the restaurants they loved before the days restrictions to create a unique in-home fine dining experience.

**Role:** Concept and name creation, resource development, front-end to back-end connections, app layout, home page, logo design, and color themes.

**Tools:** MongoDB, Mongoose ORM, Material-ui, Cloudinary, Zip Code Base API, React, Javascript, Adobe Illustrator and XD

## **EXPERIENCE**

Twenty five years of fine dining, bartending and managing restaurants in Boston, San Diego, Big Bear Lake, Cape Cod, Tucson, Cannon Beach, and Vancouver. Won several Hospitality Awards which led to the promotion as a corporate regional trainer of 32 restaurants along the East Coast in 2014.

JUNE 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

Server, Pelican Brewery, Cannon Beach, Oregon

- Implemented safety measures to protect employees and guests during the pandemic
- Participated in discussions which led to corporate-wide diversity policies

APRIL 2019 - MARCH 2020

Server, Amaro's Table, Vancouver, Washington

- Created systems that improved outdoor dining service
- Streamlined outdated feature presentation to a modern and efficient variations

JANUARY 2019 - APRIL 2019

## Food and Beverage Director/Consultant, Best Western Premier, Vancouver, Washington

- Developed a complete restaurant from concept to operational, including developing metrics to measure guest experience, food cost, and restaurant profitability
- Interviewed, hired, and counseled qualified industry professionals
- Provided training empowering staff to resolved problems efficiently ensuring both guest satisfaction and quality assurance

#### **EDUCATION**

## Certificate in Web Development: University of Washington, Seattle, WA

2020

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars is & ReactJS.

#### Certificate in Digital Design: San Diego Continuing Education, San Diego, CA

2017

A 12-month multimedia course with focus on the Adobe Creative Cloud Suite.

## Coursework in Art: Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, MA

2012

Studied Color Theory, Figure Drawing, Sculpture, and Conceptual Design.

#### Coursework in Music: Harvard Extension School, Cambridge, MA

2010

Explored Writing, Music Theory and Composition.

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

Web Designer & Developer, CodeForPDX, Portland, OR